A Guide to the Richmond Lesbian and Gay Pride Coalition Records, 1988-1993
Virginia Commonwealth University, James Branch Cabell Library
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library
Richmond Lesbian and Gay Pride Coalition Records 1988-1993
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library
M365
0.4 linear feet.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Steve Murden circa 1996.
Historical Information
The Richmond Lesbian and Gay Pride Coalition was founded in the 1980's to promote lesbian and gay pride in and around the city. The non-profit coalition organized and promoted the annual lesbian and gay pride festival, networked with other gay non-profit groups, sought to secure social justice and fair treatment for all people.
Scope and Content
Records, 1988-1993, of the Richmond Lesbian and Gay Pride Coalition, principally consisting of clippings, correspondence, flyers, meeting minutes, and treasurer's files pertaining to the organization and its main annual event the Richmond Lesbian and Gay Pride Festival. There are also biographical sketches for board of directors nominees. Correspondence is exchanged between the board of directors and other committees with local vendors, RLGPC members, and local government officials concerning the Pride Festival.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically.
Contents List
- Articles of Incorporation and By-laws, n.d. (Folder 1)
- Award guidelines form, n.d. (Folder 2)
- Biographical sketch of Steve Murden, 1990 (Folder 3)
- Board of Directors ballots, n.d. (Folder 4)
- Board of Directors candidates' biographical sketches, 1990-1992 (Folder 5)
- Board of Directors list of members, 1990 and n.d. (Folder 6)
- Board of Directors meeting agendas, 1990-1991 (Folder 7)
- Board of Directors minutes, 1990-1991 (Folder 8)
- Clippings, 1991 (Folder 9)
- Correspondence, 1990-1992 (Folder 10)
- Door prizes drawing blank forms, n.d. (Folder 11)
- Film Festival committee files, 1990 (Folder 12)
- Flyers, 1990-1991 (Folder 13)
- Fundraising Committee files, 1991 (Folder 14)
- Gayellow Pages application form, n.d. (Folder 15)
- Letterhead, n.d. (Folder 16)
- Long Range committee minutes, 1991 (Folder 17)
- Members' address list, n.d. (Folder 18)
- Membership application form, n.d. (Folder 19)
- Post-Pride Festival party invitation, n.d. (Folder 20)
- Press releases, 1991-1993 (Folder 21)
- Pride Festival closing ceremony program, 1991 (Folder 22)
- Pride Festival donation forms, 1990-1991 (Folder 23)
- Pride Festival program, 1991 (Folder 24)
- Pride Festival schedule of events, 1990 (Folder 25)
- Pride Festival schedule of events, 1991 (Folder 26)
- Pride Festival schedule of events, 1992-1993 (Folder 27)
- Pride Festival vendors fact sheet, 1991 (Folder 28)
- Pride questionnaire, 1991 (Folder 29)
- Program committee files, 1991 (Folder 30)
- Pride Festival schedules, 1990 (Folder 31)
- Gay Pride (New York City) stickers, 1991 (Folder 32)
- Pride Festival survey, 1993 (Folder 33)
- Treasurer's files, 1989-1991 (Folder 34)
- Vendor registration forms, 1991 (Folder 35)